不管夜晚还是白天,
Nighttime or daytime,
一旦你踏进了这个地方,
你就分不出日夜了.
once you get a few feet into this place,
you can't tell the difference.
或许这就是为什么它能
保持着原生态.
Probably why it's all remained
so untouched.
先生们，一步一小心.
提高警觉.
One step at a time, gentlemen.
Keep your eyes peeled.
来走这边, 在你的右边, 库.
Over this way, to your right, Coop.
哈里,
有人已经来过这儿了.
Harry,
someone's been here already.
瞧, 他们做了本该我们做的事.
Look, they did our work for us.
噢, 我的上帝.
Oh, my God.
我在发电站外面
看到了一样的鞋印.
l saw the same tracks
outside the power station.
重心在左脚.
前掌与脚跟之间有空隙.
Weight shift to the left foot.
A break in the heel.
云顿·厄尔.
Windom Earle.
厄尔来这干什么?
What would Earle be doing here?
那可是一个让人毛骨悚然
又值得深思的问题.
That's a frightening question
to contemplate.
安迪, 我需要
Andy, l'm gonna need
一幅这个岩石雕刻的
大幅精确素描图.
an accurate large-scale
rendering of this petroglyph.
哈里, 我们要给布里格斯少校
打电话.
Harry, let's get Major Briggs
on the horn.
你想他到警局
和我们见面吗?
You want him to meet us
at the station?
对.
That's the ticket.
从前,
Once upon a time,
有一个至高无上的地方
there was a place of great goodness
叫守日门.
called the White Lodge.
温顺的小鹿在那儿嬉戏
沉浸在快乐之中, 到处欢声笑语.
Gentle fawns gamboled there
amidst happy, laughing spirits.
空气中瀰漫着天真无邪
和欣喜的气息.
The sounds of innocence and joy
filled the air.
雨露, 是甘露美酒
滋润着人们的心灵
And when it rained, it rained
sweet nectar that infused one's heart
滋润着人们在生活中
渴望的真理和美丽.
with a desire to live life
in truth and beauty.
总的来说, 真是一个惨白恐怖的地方,
到处充斥着贞节的酸臭味.
Generally speaking, a ghastly place,
reeking of virtue's sour smell.
到处都塞满了
那些呢喃的祷告者
Engorged with
the whispered prayers
那些虔诚跪拜的母亲,
呀呀啼哭的初生儿,
of kneeling mothers,
mewling newborns,
还有傻子, 老老少少,
毫无理由的被强迫着去做好事.
and fools, young and old,
compelled to do good without reason.
但我很高兴的指出
我们的故事还没完结
But l am happy to point out
that our story does not end
在这个过度肉麻又卑鄙的
悲惨世界里.
in this wretched place
of saccharine excess.
原来还有另一个地方.
恰恰相反.
For there's another place.
lts opposite.
那是一个几乎
超乎想像力的地方,
A place of almost
unimaginable power,
塞满了暗黑能量
和恶毒秘密.
chock-full of dark forces
and vicious secrets.
没有祷告者敢进入
这个吓人的无底洞.
No prayers dare enter
this frightful maw.
在那儿的亡灵才不关心什么
善行或圣僧似的祈祷.
Spirits there care not for good deeds
or priestly invocations.
他们会把你的肉
从你的骨头上撕扯下来
They are as like
to rip the flesh from your bone
作为欢迎你愉快一天的开始.
as greet you with a happy good day.
如果好好加以利用,
那么，在这撕心裂肺，尖叫四起
And if harnessed,
these spirits in this hidden land
的地方里隐藏的
亡灵们就会为
of unmuffled screams
and broken hearts
它们的新主人提供无边的法力
will offer up a power so vast
好让他随心所欲的
把世界玩弄于股掌之中.
that its bearer might reorder
the earth itself to his liking.
我现在所讲的这个地方
就被称作守夜门.
Now, this place l speak of
is known as the Black Lodge.
而我决意要找到它.
And l intend to find it.
嘿, 伙计,
Hey, man,
这故事很酷啊,
the story's cool,
但你答应过我有啤酒喝的.
but you promised me beer.
你还跟我说
会有派对的啊.
You told me
there was gonna be a party.
我说啊, 什么破烂守日门守夜门?
照我说, 有什么大不了的?
l mean, White Lodge, Black Lodge?
l mean, what's the big deal?
时间刚好, 年轻人.
万事有道.
ln time, young man.
Everything in time.
我想我再也不会见到第二个
如乔西般可爱的女孩了.
l think that l shall never see
a girl as lovely as Josie.
当她走进房间,
When she walks into a room,
花儿也为之敬礼,
the flowers all stood up,
人去楼空,
to room,
命啊,
doom,
如烟, 如梦...
fume, gloom...
我想我再也不会见到第二个
如乔西般可爱的女孩了.
l think that l shall never see
a girl as lovely as Josie.
当她踏进房间,
所有的花朵都要为之绽放.
When she walks into a room,
the flowers were all abloom.
- 噢, 乔西.
- 喂, 你的感伤还有完没完啊，快停止.
- Oh, Josie.
- Oh, stop your incessant moping.
快来帮我看看这个该死的盒子.
Give me a hand with this damn box.
你到底想我
为你做什么呢?
What exactly
would you like me to do?
打开它. 我已经试了好几天了.
Open it. l've been trying for days.
托马斯·埃卡死的时候
把这个留给我.
Thomas Eckhardt
left this to me when he died.
我要它打开,
马上打开.
And l want it opened,
l want it opened now.
那好, 让我们先来看看.
Well, let's have a look-see here.
你有钥匙吗?
Do you have a key?
你说呢? 如果我有钥匙的话,
它早就打开了.
lf l had a key, it would be open,
don't you think?
嗯, 它连个钥匙孔
都没有.
Well, it doesn't even have
a keyhole.
是一个暗箱.
lt's a puzzle box.
我以前在关岛的工艺品店
见过一个类似的.
l saw one of these
at a crafts emporium on Guam.
我当时正和一对叫杜力图的双胞胎
在那儿大肆挥霍.
l was there taking a little R and R
with the Doolittle twins.
荒唐的你简直
不敢相信,
There was a monkey show
you wouldn't believe,
那个戴尔·杜力图--
就是, 他是2个里大的那个--
and Dale Doolittle--
Now, he was the larger of the two--
说到这，我想起来了, 就双胞胎来说,
他们不算长得特别相像.
Come to think of it, for twins,
they weren't all that much alike.
彼得!
Peter!
不好意思, 小松狮.
Sorry, poodle.
这机关就是把其中一条配上对
仅此而已.
The trick is to fit the pieces together
just so.
那要多久?
And how long will it take?
难说, 可能几年.
Well, this could take years.
雪, 我已经对将来的事
考虑了很多.
Shel, l've been doing a lot of thinking
about the future.
以及怎么
在这个世界混下去.
And what it takes
to get ahead in the world.
我读书看报, 看电视,
忽然间，我灵光一闪:
l'm reading up, watching TV,
suddenly it hits me:
原来成功的秘诀就是.
The secret to success.
只要人长得漂亮
就可以呼风唤雨.
Beautiful people
get everything they want.
- 波比.
- 真的, 想想看啊.
- Bobby.
- Yeah, think about it.
你啥时见过
一个金发美人
When's the last time you saw
a beautiful blonde
会被判死刑的?
go to the electric chair?
你就非常美丽, 雪莉.
You are very beautiful, Shelly.
我想是时候要好好利用
我们的优势了，美人计.
And l think it's time we took advantage
of this beautiful people's conspiracy.
那你认识哪个参议员能和我结婚吗?
Know any senators l can marry?
先看看这个.
Check it out.
双峰小姐.
Miss Twin Peaks.
一旦我们赢得了桂冠,
宝贝, 天界无限啊.
Once we get that crown on your head,
baby, the sky is the limit.
做梦, 波比,
还有客人等着我的.
Dream on, Bobby,
l have tables to wait on.
雪莉, 听着, 别和我争执了.
Shelly, listen, don't argue with me.
波比说了算,
你懂了吗?
Bobby's in charge,
you understand?
我们今天下午
一定要去报名.
We have to enlist
by this afternoon.
亲爱的，有件事
我想要你为我做.
There's something
l want you to do for me, darling.
只要身心能承受的
我都会为你做.
l'll do anything
that body and mind can stand.
难道这几天以来
还不能证明么?
Surely the last few days
have been proof of that?
你尽管说吧.
You just name it.
我要赢
双峰小姐比赛.
l wanna win
the Miss Twin Peaks contest.
你就尽管说吧.
You just name it.
我要赢
双峰小姐比赛.
l wanna win
the Miss Twin Peaks contest.
哦, 这还用说吗.
Oh, of course.
嗯, 我以前做过一，两次
颇有名气的演讲.
Well, l've been known
to make a speech or two in my time.
我会连夜辅导你怎么作选美演讲.
l'll coach you day and night.
噢, 听着, 甜心.
宝贝, 我不是这个意思.
Oh, now, sweetheart.
Baby, that's not what l'm talking about.
现在, 你是评委之一.
Now, you're one of the judges.
你可以左右结果的.
You can guarantee it.
但是-- 但是...
But-- But...
那是错误的.
lt would be wrong.
那好, 听着, 亲爱的--
Well, now, darling--
亲爱的, 那是爱的表现.
Darling, it would be love.
仅此而已.
That's all.
你知道,
我愿意为你做任何事, 拉娜.
You know,
l'd do anything for you, Lana.
你是知道的.
You know that.
是的, 爱人, 我知道.
Yes, lover, l do.
- 早上好, 安妮.
- 嗨. 吃早餐吗?
- Good morning, Annie.
- Hi. Breakfast?
我有4个如饥似渴的公安
在外面的巡逻车上等着呢.
l've got four hungry lawmen
out in the police cruiser.
我们要甜甜圈和咖啡. 热的.
We need donuts and coffee. Hot.
2杯黑咖啡, 2杯白咖啡,
不加糖, 麻烦你了.
Two black, two white,
no sugars, please.
- 马上来.
- 噢, 还有，安妮?
- Coming right up.
- Oh, and Annie?
我想借这个机会
邀请你
l'd like to take this opportunity
to ask you
参加今天下午的业余自然研究
不止你是否愿意伴我同行?
if you'd like to accompany me
on a nature study this afternoon?
自然研究?
Nature study?
好啊.
Sure.
那太棒了.
How wonderful.
什么?
What?
每当我和你说话,
我都既紧张又兴奋
When l talk to you,
l get a tingling sensation
从胃到脚趾头，浑身发抖.
in my toes and in my stomach.
有意思.
That's interesting.
我觉得
跟喝了咖啡没太大关系.
l don't think
it has anything to do with coffee.
- 我去拿甜甜圈.
- 谢谢.
- l'll get those donuts.
- Thanks.
雪莉?
Shelly?
你很美, 明白吗?
You are beautiful, got it?
把它用作你的优势.
Use it to your advantage.
"这世间一切的甜蜜之事价值何在,
''What is all this sweet work worth,
如果汝不吻我?"
if thou kiss not me?''
你刚说什么?
l beg your pardon?
哦, 是一首无名诗
也不知谁送来的.
Oh, it was an anonymous poem
someone sent me.
雪莉,
Shelly,
我需要立即看这首诗.
l need to see this poem immediately.
好的.
Okay.
它被分成3部分,
我们每个人有一部分.
lt was in three pieces,
we each got a piece.
- 唐娜, 欧蕊和我.
- 谢谢你.
- Donna, Audrey and me.
- Thank you.
这个我要留着.
l need to keep this.
- 好.
- 谢谢你.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
一打甜甜圈, 4杯咖啡,
2黑, 2白, 无糖.
A dozen donuts, four cups of coffee,
two black, two white, no sugar.
谢谢你.
Thank you.
- 库珀探员?
- 是.
- Agent Cooper?
- Yes.
今天下午?
This afternoon?
我会来这儿找你.
四点整.
l'll meet you right here.
Four o'clock sharp.
"山之吻.
''Mountains kiss.
波延绵.
Waves clasp.
花儿..."
Flower...''
这都什么玩意儿啊?
What's this all about?
是一首诗, 哈里. 被撕成3份.
lt's a poem, Harry. Torn into thirds.
分别送到了雪莉·强生, 欧蕊·荷恩
和唐娜·海沃德那里
Sent to Shelly Johnson, Audrey Horne
and Donna Hayward
云顿·厄尔干的.
from Windom Earle.
你是说3个女孩
都给厄尔盯上了?
You mean Earle's contacted
all three girls?
你肯定?
Are you sure?
看那山峰高耸入云,
犹如波涛延绵不断
See the mountains kiss high heaven
And the waves clasp one another
没有一朵姐妹花会被宽恕
如果它鄙视它的兄弟
No sister-flower would be forgiven
lf it disdained its brother
是我曾经送给凯若琳的一首诗.
A poem l once sent to Caroline.
我希望这不过
是个嘲笑, 哈里.
l hope it's nothing more
than a taunt, Harry.
厄尔喜欢用他的能力去伤及无辜性命
以此来显示自己变态的自豪感.
Earle takes perverse pride in his ability
to insinuate himself into innocent lives.
那, 我们尽可能快的
去找女孩们谈谈.
Well, let's talk to the girls
as soon as we can.
看他们能记起些什么.
See what they remember.
唐娜·海沃德的诗.
Donna Hayward's poem.
欧蕊·荷恩在西雅图.
明天之前不会回来.
Audrey Horne is in Seattle.
She won't be back till tomorrow.
布里格斯少校来了
在会议室.
Major Briggs is here
in the conference room.
豪克?
Hawk?
能麻烦你给我拿一下
里欧·强生的逮捕报告?
Would you please bring me
Leo Johnson's arrest report?
里欧?
Leo?
怎么了?
What's going on?
我要把碎片连起来, 哈里.
Putting the pieces together, Harry.
布伦南警官?
Deputy Brennan?
据我记忆,
你现在正画的这条线
As l remember,
the line you are drawing
应该一直沿着下方画,
而不是打横.
should proceed downward,
not across.
你是怎么知道的?
How did you know that?
布里格斯少校?
感谢你的到来，先生.
Major Briggs?
Thank you, sir, for coming in.
少校, 我们需要你的帮助.
Major, we need your help.
但我不能够准确的向你
描述如何或为什么.
But l am unable to accurately
describe for you how or why.
继续说.
Go on.
双峰警察局
现在陷入了
The Twin Peaks Sheriff's Department
is currently involved
几宗离奇的调查案中.
in several disparate investigations.
被通缉的重罪犯里欧·强生
失踪了.
The disappearance
of known felon, Leo Johnson.
我的前搭档
兼杀人嫌疑犯
The appearance
of my former partner
云顿·厄尔,
失踪了.
and suspected murderer,
Windom Earle.
还有在一个叫猫头鹰山洞
的地方发现了
And the discovery of petroglyphs
of an unknown origin
一副来历不明的岩石壁画.
in a place called Owl Cave.
现在, 按一般逻辑
看来
Now, it would seem
logic would dictate
这些案子
似乎都是单独分离的个案.
that these investigations
be considered separate entities.
然而, 我相信事情另有跷蹊.
However, l believe otherwise.
我相信这一系列神秘事件
并不是单独存在的,
l believe that these mysteries
are not separate entities,
事实上, 它们不过是同一首诗上
的补充诗句罢了.
but are in fact, complementary verses
of the same song.
现在, 我尚未把它听的很真切.
Now, l cannot hear it yet.
但我已经能感觉到它了.
But l can feel it.
那足够让我
着手进行下去.
And that is enough
for me to proceed.
我要怎么做才能真正帮助你呢?
How exactly may l help you?
我需要知道
一切有关
l need to know everything
that there is to know
云顿·厄尔在参与
蓝皮书项目时的事.
about Windom Earle's work
with Project Blue Book.
我失踪后，在高度机密安检的资格
就被迅速撤销了.
My security clearance was revoked
shortly after my disappearance.
你有能力入侵
蓝皮书档案吗?
And your ability to access
these Blue Book files?
现在, 问题不单在于入侵档案.
Now, the issue is not one of access.
而是, 基于某些道德准则，
我必须考虑.
However, there are certain
moral judgments l must consider.
是的, 先生, 我理解.
Yes, sir, l understand.
这些信息能帮助你
防止再有人伤亡吗?
Will this information help you
to prevent future loss of life?
那当然了.
Most assuredly.
这是你在猫头鹰山洞找到的
那幅巖壁画的复制品吗?
ls this a copy of the petroglyph
you found in Owl Cave?
安迪?
Andy?
先生.
Sir.
你觉得这眼熟吗?
Are you familiar with this?
嗯, 我梦见过它.
Well, l've dreamed it.
或者在某处见过它, 反正就见过.
Or seen it somewhere, somehow.
你会照你说的办.
l will do what you ask.
- 里欧·强生的逮捕报告.
- 干的好, 豪克.
- Leo Johnson's arrest report.
- Good work, Hawk.
先生们,
里欧·强生的脑损伤
Gentlemen,
the damage to Leo Johnson
会改变某些
书写特征.
would alter
certain handwriting characteristics.
然而, 基本形态
仍是一样的.
However, the basic style
would remain the same.
这首诗,
This poem,
是云顿·厄尔寄来的,
由里欧·强生抄写.
sent by Windom Earle,
was transcribed by Leo Johnson.
荷恩先生.
Mr. Horne.
荷恩先生, 无疑你该知道,
还有几小时
Mr. Horne, as you are no doubt aware,
there are but scant hours
我们的品酒会马上就要开始了
until our wine-tasting benefit begins
但我在哪儿都
找不着你的女儿.
and l can't find
your daughter anywhere.
欧蕊要去西雅图一天
Audrey is in Seattle for the day.
可是, 我肯定我们的前台人员
将会协助你.
However, l'm sure that our concierge
will be able to assist you.
前台人员.
The concierge.
是的, 这很重要.
Yes, capital.
谢谢你, 荷恩先生.
Thank you, Mr. Horne.
噢, ...先生
Oh, Mr...
- 理查·揣眉.
- 揣眉, 是, 对.
- Richard Tremayne.
- Tremayne, yes, right.
- 男装部.
- 男装部, 好的.
- Men's fashions.
- Men's fashions, of course.
告诉我,
Tell me,
你的鼻子怎么了?
how is your nose?
哦, 荷恩先生, 不用担心，没事.
Oh, Mr. Horne, think nothing of it.
一个鼻子，比起更伟大而美好的
慈善服务，不过是一点小小付出.
A nose is a small price to pay
in the service of a greater good.
那好, 当然由我们来
支付所有医疗费用.
Well, we will, of course,
pay any medical expenses.
真好.
How kind.
还有一件事
员工的多种赔偿金
One might also think
workers' compensation
或许也应考虑在内.
in some variety will be involved.
那倒容易.
Easily done.
这也很重要的, 荷恩先生.
Capital, Mr. Horne.
我会提醒我的律师.
l'll alert my attorney.
"我要提醒我的律师."
''l will alert my attorney.''
有时做坏事的冲动
Sometimes the urge to do bad
真的几乎是压倒性的.
is nearly overpowering.
尽情喝吧, 我的朋友. 我们来庆祝.
Drink up, my friend. We celebrate.
庆祝?
我的手臂都动不了.
Celebrate?
l can barely move my arms.
你这短暂的一生
活的脏臭，阴暗又卑微.
You have lived your short life
in odium and obscurity.
但现在, 人生的最后,
But now, at the last,
你将会步上更大的舞台.
you will step upon the larger stage.
我得承认, 我羡慕你.
l must confess, l envy you.
你的旅程远在想像
之外的一点开始了.
Your journey begins
at a point beyond imagining.
谁知道它从那儿
去到哪儿旅行?
Who knows where it might travel
from there?
我快憋死了.
l'm pumped.
嘿, 这要干嘛, 像那个,
参加什么紫丁香巡游吗?
Hey, is this for, like,
the Lilac Parade or what?
不, 不是巡游, 我的朋友,
肯定不是.
No, not a parade, my friend,
not exactly.
那好, 能忙上的点忙，还有其他什么的
我真的觉得挺酷的
Well, l'm real cool
about helping out and everything
但我怎么才能从这个东西里出来?
but how do l get out of this thing?
你不出来.
You don't.
里欧?
Leo?
给我箭.
Fetch me an arrow.
箭?
Arrow?
哇, 伙计.
Whoa, man.
我可不欣赏恶作剧.
l do not appreciate practical jokes.
里欧, 箭?
Leo, the arrow?
不.
No.
呀, 别电击那怪胎.
Jeez, don't zap the geek.
没有他我怎么
喝我的啤酒啊--? 你知道么.
How am l supposed to get
my beer without--? You know.
哥们. 那很痛吧.
Dude. That hurts.
给我箭.
Fetch me the arrow.
谢谢你, 里欧.
Thank you, Leo.
箭干嘛用, 伙计?
What's with the arrow, man?
你要干嘛?
What are you doing?
这可不好玩.
This isn't funny.
- 安静.
- 喂, 你到底要搞什么鬼啊?
- Be still.
- Well, what the hell are you doing?
想想所有不幸的罪人
Think of all the hapless sinners
都想知道哪里才是
他们灵魂栖息的最终目的地.
wondering where
their souls' destination lies.
为了什么?
For what?
就是为了得到
一个简单问题的答案.
To gain the answer
to a simple question.
我的灵魂将会在哪里甦醒?
Where will my spirit awake?
我死后又会去到何种世界呢?
What life am l given after this life?
这个死魂灵一样的问题，如瘟疫般
永远折磨着人那颗可怜的良心.
This grave question has plagued
man's sorry conscience for eons.
而现在, 你, 你这幸运男孩.
And now, you, you lucky boy.
你即将揭晓答案了.
You have the answer.
马上.
Now.
双峰小姐
裁判规章委员会现在开会.
Miss Twin Peaks Judging and Rules
Committee is now in session.
你知道么, 今年将会
非常令人兴奋.
You know, this year
is going to be very exciting.
- 现在，我们--
- 非常兴奋.
- Now we--
- Very exciting.
今年将会
非常，非常令人兴奋.
This year is going to be
very, very exciting.
谢谢你, 杜恩.
Thank you, Dwayne.
现在, 第一件事.
Now, first order of business.
本·荷恩先生已请求
以委员会之友的身份
Mr. Ben Horne has asked
to address the committee
向委员会之辞.
as a friend of the committee.
我对此没有异议.
l don't have any objection to that.
请致辞, 本.
Address away, Ben.
谢谢你.
Thank you.
这, 杜恩, 让我先恭喜你
新近订婚.
And, Dwayne, let me congratulate you
on your recent engagement.
非常感谢你.
Thank you very much.
她是一个可爱的女人
我祝愿你幸福无比.
She's a lovely woman
and l wish you much happiness.
真的, 非常感谢你.
Well, thank you very much.
先生们.
Gentlemen.
我的意图很简单.
My purpose is simple.
以往那些挤眉弄眼, 穿着泳装乱颤颠
的选美节早已过时了.
The age of the ogling, swim-suited
jiggle festivals of the past is dead.
而双峰小姐, 我相信,
是端庄的,
Miss Twin Peaks, l believe,
and rightly,
现在，这是一个展示全体女性
素质的庆典.
is now a celebration
of the totality of a woman's qualities.
美要被赋予
一个更广泛的定义
Beauty has taken on
a broader definition
包括才智, 精神境界, 价值观, 创意.
to include mind, spirit, values, ideas.
基于这些, 先生们,
And for taking this step, gentlemen,
我为你们鼓掌喝彩.
l applaud you.
他这是在推销什么?
你在推销什么?
What's he selling?
What are you selling?
市长先生, 我就不妨
直说了吧.
Mr. Mayor, let me get
right to the point.
双峰小姐是一件大事
要为此搜索一个主题.
Miss Twin Peaks is an event
in search of a theme.
那, 我提议很简单.
Now, what l propose is simple.
今年演讲的主题应该是
如何拯救我们的森林.
The topic of this year's speeches
should be how to save our forests.
符合潮流, 切题,有意义
全球化，还有就是...
lt's now, it's relevant,
it's global and it's...
要么, 更清楚地说,
先生们, 就是我们.
Well, to put it plainly,
gentlemen, it's us.
明摆着, 你就是要和
格斯伍发展计划对着干
Of course, your opposition
to the Ghostwood development plans
除此之外
就没别的了?
wouldn't have anything
to do with this?
皮特,
Pete,
我讨厌你这话的弦外之音.
l resent your implication.
这里的环境问题可能
阻碍了一些本地的经济
The environmental issues here
dwarf any parochial business concerns
但这关系到你，我，他
that l, or you, or anyone else
任何一个人都脱不开.
might be pursuing.
我们对此会从长计议的.
We'll take it under advisement.
那是我全部
的冀望了.
That's the most
that l could hope for.
先生们, 谢谢你们的宝贵时间.
市长先生.
Gentlemen, thank you for your time.
Mr. Mayor.
他以为他能装神弄鬼.
He thinks he can pull a fast one.
这个想法有其价值.
The idea has merit.
我个人倒赞成这意见.
l'm in favor of it myself.
- 波比.
- 嘿, 领导.
- Bobby.
- Hey, chief.
别忘了
去干洗的事儿, 好吧?
Don't forget
the dry-cleaning, all right?
谢谢.
Thanks.
第一位候选人
麻烦到委员会这来
Will the first candidate
please approach the committee?
拉娜? 过来吧, 小蜜糖.
Lana? Come on up, honey.
这不搞关系吗，没人管吗?
Does anybody smell a fix here?
我办不到, 波比.
l can't do this, Bobby.
我这辈子，从来没发表过
演说.
l have never made a speech before
in my life.
我四年级，在班上的加德纳太太面前
读过一份书报告
l read a book report in the fourth grade
in front of Mrs. Gardner's class
然后就在全班面前
昏过去了.
and l passed out
right in front of the whole room.
你会做的很棒的, 宝贝娃娃.
我会帮你做讲辞写手.
You'll do great, doll.
l'm gonna be your speech writer.
你一定会很棒的.
别担心, 好吗?
You're gonna be great.
Don't worry, okay?
-给你. 祝好运.
-唐娜? 你也来报名吗?
-Here you go. Good luck.
-Donna? Are you entering too?
- 是啊, 你也是?
- 噢, 我绝不会错过.
- Yeah, you too?
- Oh, l wouldn't miss it for the world.
- 这不很令人兴奋吗?
- 就是.
- lsn't it exciting?
- Yes.
就是.
Yes.
迈克, 好长一段时间没见了.
Mike, it's a long time no see.
我本来想问你跑哪儿去了
但我想我现在知道了.
l'd ask where you've been
keeping yourself but l think l know.
- 这真的很吓人哦, 迈克.
- 并不像你想的那样.
- This is very scary, Mike.
- lt's not what you think.
不像我想的那样.
你怎么知道我怎么想?
lt's not what l think.
What do you think l think?
你在想我和一个
老女人约会.
You think l'm going out
with an older woman.
我在想不知你突然哪儿来的兴趣
竟然过起了化石生涯.
l think l don't know where you got this
sudden interest in the life of fossils.
是啊, 但...
Yeah, but...
这真不是你想的那样.
lt's not what you think.
迈克, 拜托了.
Mike, big favor.
给我讲个明白吧.
Clear this up for me.
我不会期望你理解.
l wouldn't expect you to understand.
我会努力去理解的.
l will strive to be understanding.
你有没有试想过
Do you have any idea
一个性成熟和神力
what a combination of sexual maturity
的结合体
能导致什么结果吗?
and superhuman strength
can result in?
对不起.
Sorry.
凯萨琳, 如果你能
告诉我有关她的, 任何事--
Catherine, if there's anything
you can tell me about her, anything--
什么都好
反正能帮我理解整件事的.
Anything at all
that might help me understand.
比如?
For instance?
是什么
令她做出那些事的?
What made her do
the things she did?
在她背后又是什么?
What was she after?
这些问题
我也问过自己很多遍了.
l've been asking myself
a lot of the same things.
凯萨琳?
Catherine?
我需要去理解它.
l need to understand.
我想在她早年的生涯里,
她肯定是学到什么教训
l think that early in her life,
she must have learned the lesson
以致她认为要生存
就必须伪装成别人想看到,
that she could survive by being
what other people wanted to see,
得到的东西.
by showing them that.
至于她私己的真面目
到底还剩下多少,就难说了
And whatever was left
of her private self,
她或许从未给任何人
展示过.
she may never have shown
to anyone.
- 那么，她以前说的那些故事, 谎言都是--?
- 哦, 天晓得?
- So all the stories, the lies were--?
- Well, who knows?
对她来说，它们不见得
不真实啊.
They may not have seemed
untrue to her.
随机应变
是她永远的信条.
What she needed to believe was
always shifting to suit the moment.
尽管她试图对我和我的家族
做了那些坏事,
ln spite of all the things
she tried to do to me and my family,
但我却好奇的发现
很难为此而恨她.
l find it curiously hard
to hate her for it.
哦, 她是...
Well, she was...
她是如此如此的美丽.
She was so very beautiful.
这儿有条线索
或许能对我们俩有帮助.
There may be a clue
that could benefit both of us.
是什么?
What's that?
托马斯·埃卡死的时候
留了这个给我.
Thomas Eckhardt left this to me
when he died.
它的出现让我觉得这可能
和乔西有什么关系.
lt occurred to me that it might have
something to do with Josie.
里面是什么?
What's inside?
我不知道.
我一直无法打开它.
l don't know.
l haven't been able to open it.
让我看看.
Let me see.
- 啊, 没盖子, 没--
- 没.
- Well, there's no lid, there's--
- No.
也没扣子.
There's no clasp.
哇喂, 波波.
Wowee, Bob.
我们已经有很多美女
来参加今年的比赛了.
Have we got some beauties
in the contest this year.
你好, 哈里.
Hello, Harry.
好像镇上的每个少女
都来排队准备要大秀一番--
Seems like every gal in town
is lined up to take a shot at the--
快说, 够运气把
这东西打开吗?
Say, have you had any luck
with this thing?
笨手笨脚.
Butterfingers.
我的圣魔草啊.
Holy moly.
这是什么?
What is it?
- 给我.
- 等等, 小松狮.
- Give it to me.
- Just a second, poodle.
别紧张, 我只是拿着它而已.
Now, l held it just so.
以前，我每个夏天都在这游泳.
一周游2，3次.
l used to swim here every summer.
Two or three times a week.
那我选对地方了.
这儿真美.
Then l made a good choice.
lt's beautiful.
我总是觉得大自然比人
要亲近的多了.
l always felt closer to nature
than l did to people.
- 为什么?
- 我从来没有太多朋友.
- Why?
- l never had many friends.
而诺玛却是大众情人.
Norma was always Miss Popularity.
她总是轻易就
能面对外界.
She was always moving
toward the world.
而我却正好
相反.
And l was always
moving away from it.
- 大多时候, 我都活在自己的世界里.
- 那样的社区不坏嘛.
- Lived in my head, mostly.
- That's not a bad neighborhood.
但有些奇怪的
邻居.
There's some pretty strange
neighbors.
- 有很多男友吗?
- 没有.
- Many boyfriends?
- No.
真的?
Really?
对, 我有过一个.
Well, l had one.
高中?
High school?
大学.
Senior year.
是什么原因
会让你跑到修道院里去?
Have anything to do
with why you went into the convent?
不好意思, 我不想谈这个，
你介意吗?
l'm sorry, do you mind
if we don't talk about it?
没关系.
随你喜欢，我们以后再谈吧.
Not at all.
We can talk about whatever you'd like.
我想回到现实生活中来.
l wanna come back to the world.
我受惊太长时间了.
l was so frightened for so long.
我理解.
l understand.
逃避并不是办法
恐惧是不会因此而消失的.
Hiding from your fear
doesn't make your fear go away.
反倒令它更强烈.
Makes it stronger.
所以我必须面对它.
亲自去面对它.
So l had to face it.
l had to face myself.
而且我必须在这直面它.
因为这里就是出错的地方.
And l had to do it here.
Where everything went so wrong.
安妮, 我知道事情看来
有多么的无望.
Annie, l know how hopeless
things can seem.
我知道你坠入
了黑暗的隧道.
l know about the dark tunnel
you can fall into.
这是我离开之前发生的.
lt happened before l went away.
为了那个男孩.
lt happened because of that boy.
在我身上发生过类似的事.
Something similar happened to me.
它简直让我想从此
消失在世上.
lt made me wanna disappear
from the world.
正因为如此,
或许我能帮助你.
Because of that,
maybe l can help you.
- 我对你还不是很了解.
- 不了解.
- l don't know you very well.
- No.
我正试着学会
如何去相信我的直觉.
l'm trying to learn
how to trust my instincts.
那它们怎么说?
What are they saying?
信任.
Trust.
晚上好. 晚上好, 各位.
Good evening. Evening, all.
欢迎来到
我们的评酒晚宴.
And welcome
to our oenophiliac soiree.
在持续不断的系列
公共活动中,
Another in a continuing series
of public events,
这又是一个由荷恩企业赞助的,
sponsored by Horne lndustries,
有益于停止格斯伍发展计划
的举措.
to benefit the Stop Ghostwood
Development movement.
品什么东西?
Ono-what?
- 可能是葡萄酒吧.
- 那么,
- Something to do with wine.
- And now,
品尝开始了.
to the tasting.
拉娜, 露西,
Lana, Lucy,
你们愿意帮我倒酒吗, 劳驾了.
if you'd like to help me pour, please.
今晚我们品尝的第一款
是红葡萄酒.
Our first wines this evening
are reds.
有些学派
他们会说,
There are some schools of thought
who, of course, say,
除了红葡萄酒之外，其他都不能算葡萄酒.
there are no other wines but reds.
请说, 安迪?
Yes, Andy?
我知道还有白葡萄酒
和气泡酒.
There are also white wines
and sparkling wines.
谢谢你, 安迪.
Thank you, Andy.
现在我们杯里都倒进酒了,
让我们首先来尝试--
And now that we're all poured,
let us first examine--
还没开始呢, 安迪,
看在老天爷的份上.
Don't taste it yet, Andy,
for heaven's sake.
吐出来.
Spit it out.
对不起.
Sorry.
没关系.
That's all right.
我们来这, 就是为了学习.
That's what we're here for, to learn.
好了, 回到酒上.
Now, to the wine.
我们必须先用鼻子
去鉴别酒香
We must first examine
the nose of the wine
看它能否告诉我们
什么花香蕴含在里面.
to see what it can tell us
about its bouquet.
而我们要用什么才能做到呢...
And we do that by...
用嗅觉.
By smelling.
非常好, 拉娜.
Very good, Lana.
举起玻璃杯, 这样.
Lift the glass, thusly.
然后，当我们用力
晃杯的同时,
And while rolling the wine
vigorously around in the glass,
深满的呼吸酒香.
we breathe deeply and fully.
很好.
Very good.
那现在, 我们品尝第一口,
猛烈汹涌的吞一大口.
And now, we take our first taste,
a big boisterous gulp.
然后让它在我们的
整个颚腔中翻腾.
And we roll it around
our entire palate.
我们试着让
And we try to reach
这些小味蕾仅仅延伸
到舌根后面就够了,
those little taste buds stuck
way far at the back of the tongue,
记住不要吞下去哦.
remembering not to swallow.
太出色了.
Excellent.
好了, 吐出来.
And now, we spit.
于是，他从暗处慢慢走出,
把死女孩扔在身后.
So he came slowly out of the shadows,
leaving the dead girl behind.
然后我说, "你在向前一步
我就让你开天窗."
And l said, ''You take one more step
and l will ventilate you.''
然后发生了什么?
And then what happened?
一个简短但感人的葬礼.
lt was a brief, but touching funeral.
戴尔, 真高兴赶得及见上你一面.
Dale, glad l caught up with you.
出租车正在外面等着呢
我马上要上路了.
Got the rental fired up outside
and about ready to hit the road.
戈登, 超级棒
你离开前能被我们赶上.
Gordon, super
we caught you before you left.
- 你快回来.
- 我会的, 库.
- You hurry back.
- l will, Coop.
- 还记的安妮吗?
- 我当然记的.
- Remember Annie?
- Of course l do.
看来，这个双峰镇
到处都是美人啊.
This world of Twin Peaks seems
to be filled with beautiful women.
虽然我只能听见一个美人的话.
Although only one l can hear.
坐下和我们一起吃馅饼.
Join us for pie.
乐意至极.
Love to.
- 安妮?
- 谢谢.
- Annie?
- Thanks.
3人份.
Three each.
- 雪莉, 介意我们俩分享一个吗?
- 不介意.
- Shelly, do you mind if we share?
- No.
库, 常言道
爱让世界转动.
Coop, they say that love
makes the world go around.
谁能获其所需
谁就是这世上最幸运的人.
Makes people who need people
the luckiest people in the world.
虽然从来没人说过
这事他妈的还能治愈失聪呢.
Although they never said a doggoned
thing about a cure for hearing loss.
雪莉, 你真是个神迹使者.
Shelly, you are a miracle worker.
天僊下凡.
And a goddess sent from heaven.
我不过是餐厅里的一个女招待.
l'm a waitress in a diner.
之前，我从未被人
比喻过天僊.
l've never been compared
to a goddess before.
这样, 雪莉,
你只是还不知道自身的价值.
Well, Shelly,
you just don't know your own value.
库, 她真是一个珍稀尤物
你不觉得吗?
Coop, she's a rare and precious
individual, don't you think?
我懂你的意思, 戈登.
l know what you mean, Gordon.
雪莉, 在我失去勇气前
转过来面对着我一会儿.
Shelly, turn around and face me
a moment before l lose my nerve.
我马上就要
离开双峰镇了,
l'm about ready
to leave Twin Peaks,
我不知道
什么时候才会再回来.
and l don't know
when l'm gonna return.
但我想你知道
能遇见你
But l want you to know
that meeting you
简直是莫大的恩赐.
has been more than a privilege.
这让我心潮澎湃.
lt's touched my heart.
我知道
如果这一刻我不吻你,
And l know
that if l don't kiss you now,
我将后悔
终身.
l'm gonna regret it
the rest of my days.
嘿!
Hey!
这算是哪门子事儿啊?
What the hell's going on?
开戏才刚开头呢,
还有四分之三
You are a witnessing a front,
three-quarter view
2个成年人分享柔情一刻
的好戏在后头，有你看的.
of two adults
sharing a tender moment.
那反应，好像他之前
从没见过人接吻似的.
Acts like he's never seen
a kiss before.
戈登?
Gordon?
再看看清楚咯, 傻小子,
又来了.
Take another look, sonny,
it's gonna happen again.
好了, 同学们,
刚啜的那一小口向我们透露了些什么呢?
All right, class,
what did that sip reveal for us?
我们正享受着什么味道呢?
What flavors are we enjoying?
有点木的口味.
Tastes kind of woody.
不, 事实上不是.
No, not really.
还有谁回答? 拉娜?
Anyone else? Lana?
- 香蕉?
- 对了.
- Banana?
- Yes.
有香蕉作点缀的意味.
那是一种模仿香蕉味的化学合成酸.
There is a hint of banana.
That's the metachloric acid.
很好.
Very good.
- 还有什么?
- 香蕉.
- What else?
- Banana.
巧克力.
Chocolate.
正确, 安迪.
Correct, Andy.
喝香蕉味酒，这不多此一举吗，
我们干吗不直接去吃香蕉船呢?
Why don't we just skip the wine
and have a banana split?
让我们来啜另一口, 好吗?
Let's take another sip, shall we?
这次吞掉,
看还有什么我们能分辨出来的.
Swallowing this time,
and see what else we can discern.
我们还能尝出其它味道吗?
What else can we taste?
还有其它什么奇妙的味道
在取悦着你的味蕾呢?
What other wonder
invites taste buds toward pleasure?
天啊, 基巴.
Gosh, Dick.
唔, 我从来都不知道
酒原来有这么多不同的特质.
Well, l just never knew wine
could have so many different qualities.
神奇吧, 不是吗?
一款真正的好酒就如同一个交响乐.
lt's amazing, isn't it?
A really good wine is like a symphony.
你有什么感觉, 露西?
And what is your reaction, Lucy?
我是孕妇.
本就不该喝酒.
l'm pregnant.
l'm not supposed to drink.
爱是地狱.
Love is hell.
什么?
Sorry?
爱, 简直就是地狱.
Love, it's hell.
印度教徒说,
爱是天堂之梯.
The Hindus say,
love is a ladder to heaven.
他们还常常赤足
行走在火炭上，以此为乐
The Hindus have also been known
to take hikes on hot coals
并因此而闻名.
for recreational purposes.
那是一种自律.
Self-discipline.
自律和爱?
好不搭调.
Self-discipline and love?
There's a bad match.
世俗之爱.
Earthly love.
还有其它的选择吗?
What other kind is there?
当你入世了,
When you're in it,
就别无选择.
no other.
那感觉就像给18铜人痛打了一顿,
却仍未得到解脱，对吧?
lt hits you like an 1 8-wheeler,
doesn't it? And there's no relief.
那只会让你感到更真切.
lt makes you feel more alive.
让你对一切都感到
更真切.
lt makes you feel more
of everything.
包括痛苦.
Pain included.
尤其是痛苦.
Especially pain.
我控制不住要去想她.
l can't stop thinking about her.
听来你的情况
颇严重.
Sounds like
you've got a pretty serious case.
哥们, 我心乱如麻,
魂牵梦绕又刻骨铭心.
Brother, l'm roped,
tied and branded.
她有同样的感觉吗?
She feel the same way?
希望是.
Here's hoping.
那你呢?
你也上了黑名单?
How about you?
You on the critical list too?
感觉我的心
给人用撬棍一下子撬开了.
Feels like someone's taking
a crowbar to my heart.
嘿, 那不赖嘛.
Hey, that's not bad.
不赖, 我想它也被封锁的
够久了.
No, l think it's been locked away
long enough.
那是好事.
That's good.
- 希望是.
- 敬你的.
- Here's hoping.
- Here's to you.
- 维乐先生? 你的电报, 先生.
- 谢谢你.
- Mr. Wheeler? Telegram for you, sir.
- Thank you.
非常感谢你.
Thank you very much.
真该死.
Damn.
- 服务生?
- 是的, 先生.
- Bellman?
- Yes, sir.
麻烦你转告前台
我要退房.
Kindly tell the front desk
l'll be checking out.
- 是, 先生.
- 谢谢你.
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
再见.
See you.
- 祝你好运.
- 你也是.
- Good luck.
- Good luck to you.
你能递一下豌豆吗, 唐娜?
Would you pass the peas, Donna?
谢谢.
Thanks.
- 妈, 能问你点事吗?
- 当然.
- Mom, could l ask you something?
- Sure.
你是怎么认识本杰明·荷恩的?
How do you know Benjamin Horne?
艾琳, 我告诉过唐娜了
Eileen, l told Donna
就是你在进行的那个
救治蓝色行星的慈善活动.
about the Heal the Planet benefit
you're working on.
救治蓝色行星?
Heal the Planet?
我看到他来这儿了.
l saw him at the house.
然后，你昨天开车去见他?
You drove to see him yesterday?
是啊, 他说他会贡献一点时间
和我们一起搞活动.
Yes, he's offered to give us
some time.
我就知道他有善心
去做几个本地的慈善活动.
l know he favors
several local charities.
那, 就一定是它了.
Well, that must have been it.
一定是其中一个慈善会
给妈妈送的玫瑰花
.
One of the local charities
must have sent Mom's roses.
你能递一下豌豆吗, 唐娜?
Would you pass the peas, Donna?
不过我觉得玫瑰真的很浪漫,
你说呢?
l think roses are really romantic,
don't you?
唐娜, 递豌豆给你妈妈.
Donna, pass your mother the peas.
在学校过的怎样?
How's school going?
好极了.
Great.
所有的女生都在为双峰小姐
兴奋不已.
All the girls are real excited
about Miss Twin Peaks.
优良传统.
我参与选美工作好多年了.
Fine tradition.
l worked with the pageant for years.
我参加了.
l entered.
真的?
Really?
你以前好像
不是特别感兴趣.
You never seemed
very interested before.
嗯, 我才想到的
Well, l guess l just figured
我可以用那笔奖学金
出国留学.
l could use the scholarship money
to study overseas.
我们觉得
那可能是个炸弹.
We thought at first
it might be a bomb.
我们没有拆弹小组,
所以安迪带了金属探测器.
We don't exactly have a bomb squad,
so Andy brought his metal detector.
如果是个炸弹, 却没有探出金属成分
也没有嘀嗒声.
lf it is a bomb, it's not metallic
and there's no ticking sound.
哈里, 曾经有过一段时间
我能以高度清晰的思维,
Harry, there was a time
when l could comprehend,
去完全理解,
云顿·厄尔扭曲的逻辑.
with a high degree of clarity,
Windom Earle's twisted logic.
但他最近的行动
让我完全不知所措.
But his actions of late
have left me completely bewildered.
他正改变棋盘
上的格局.
He is changing the pattern
of the game board.
任何能推理他下一步行动的
希望已经破灭了.
Any hope of deducing his next move
has evaporated.
安迪, 能麻烦你
指挥大家
Andy, would you please
direct everyone
躲到巡逻警车后吗?
well behind the police cruiser?
哈里. 请大家往后站.
Harry, please stand back.
可能有塑料炸药
在里面--
There could be plastic explosives
in there--
库珀大家要大家
躲到巡逻车后.
Agent Cooper wants everyone back
behind the cruiser.
--化学物,
--chemicals,
不敢想像
还会有什么鬼东西.
and whatever else
hell could imagine.
我最大的恐惧?
My greatest fear?
就是云顿·厄尔
不再按逻辑出牌.
Windom Earle
merely condescends to logic.
那留给我们的任务就艰巨了，要如何解释
一个疯子那种可怕的反覆无常.
Leaving us the task of unraveling
an insane man's terrifying caprice.